Andrew Dasburg and Grace Mott Johnson
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Andrew Dasburg Papers, circa 1900-1980, Series 1:; (Box 1-6; 6.0 linear feet)
  - Correspondence, circa 1906-1979, 1.2:
    Swaine, Ruth: 1945
    Swift, Florence Alston: 1928
    Swingle, W. W.: 1938, 1940, 1947, 1948
    Thompson, Shirley & Les: 1972, 1973
    Thompson, Vallie: 1954
    Trego, Charlotte: 1971-1978
    Trentham, Eugene (Steve): 1940, 1941, 1945
    Udell, Susan: 1978
    University of Delaware: 1974
    University of Kansas Museum of Art: 1973
    University of New Mexico: 1958
    Van Vechten, Carl: 1924, 1938
    Waldrum, Harold, 1971
    Walker, Maynard (Walker Galleries): 1941, 1942, 1947
    Walker, Bob & Mariella: 1971-1975, 1977
    Wardwell, Alice: 1951
    Watkins, Franklin: 1938, 1939
    Western Gallery of Fine Art: 1974
    Western States Arts Foundation: 1978
    White, Victor: 1939, 1941, 1943, 1944, 1974, 1977
    Whitney Museum of American Art: 1946, 1951, 1963, 1977, 1978
    Wiegand, Margarith: 1910
    Wilson, Kathy: 1951
    Wister, Frances A.: 1940
    Wister, Owen: 1933-1936, 1938-1940, 1942, 1948-1952, 1955
    Wister, Mrs. W. R.: 1937, 1940
    Wolman, Cecil & Leo: 1947, 1949, 1971, 1972, 1974, 1976, 1977
    Woodstock Artists Association, Inc.: 1975, 1977
    Woodstock Weekly: 1924
    Wright, Alice Morgan: 1928, 1938
    Wurlitzer, Helene: 1954
    Yaple, Dixie Lee: 1948
    - Correspondence with Grace Mott Johnson, circa 1906-1908, (5 folders) (Box 1, Folder 16-20)
    - Correspondence with Grace Mott Johnson, 1909, (5 folders) (Box 1, Folder 21-25)
    - Correspondence with Grace Mott Johnson, 1910, (10 folders) (Box 1, Folder 26-35)
    - Correspondence with Grace Mott Johnson, 1911, (3 folders) (Box 1, Folder 36-38)
    - Correspondence with Grace Mott Johnson, 1912-1913, (7 folders) (Box 2, Folder 1-7)
    - Correspondence with Grace Mott Johnson, 1914, (5 folders) (Box 2, Folder 8-12)
    - Correspondence with Grace Mott Johnson, 1915, (5 folders) (Box 2, Folder 13-17)
    - Correspondence with Grace Mott Johnson, 1916-1918, (5 folders) (Box 2, Folder 18-22)
    - Correspondence with Grace Mott Johnson, 1919-1929, 1940, (4 folders) (Box 2, Folder 23-26)
    - Correspondence with Grace Mott Johnson, Undated Letters, circa 1906-1940 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Correspondence with Nancy Lane, 1928, (3 folders) (Box 2, Folder 28-30)
    - Correspondence with Nancy Lane, Undated Letters, circa 1928 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Correspondence with Marina Wister Dasburg, 1935, (5 folders) (Box 2, Folder 32-36)
    - Correspondence with Marina Wister Dasburg, 1936, (4 folders) (Box 3, Folder 1-4)
    - Correspondence with Marina Wister Dasburg, 1938-1954, (8 folders) (Box 3, Folder 5-12)
    - Correspondence with Marina Wister Dasburg, Undated Letters, circa 1935-1954 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence with Alfred Dasburg, 1914, 1919-1928, (5 folders) (Box 3, Folder 14-18)
    - Correspondence with Alfred Dasburg, 1929-1938, (5 folders) (Box 3, Folder 19-23)
    - Correspondence with Alfred Dasburg, 1939-1966, (6 folders) (Box 3, Folder 24-29)
    - Correspondence with Alfred Dasburg, Undated Letters, circa 1914-1966 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - General Correspondence, 1909-1934, (7 folders) (Box 3, Folder 31-37)
    - General Correspondence, 1935-1937, (5 folders) (Box 3, Folder 38-42)
    - General Correspondence, 1938-1941, (9 folders) (Box 4, Folder 1-9)
    - General Correspondence, 1942-1945, (9 folders) (Box 4, Folder 10-18)
    - General Correspondence, 1946-1951, (9 folders) (Box 4, Folder 19-27)
    - General Correspondence, 1952-1958, (7 folders) (Box 4, Folder 28-34)
    - General Correspondence, 1959-1973, (7 folders) (Box 5, Folder 1-7)
    - General Correspondence, 1974-1979, (9 folders) (Box 5, Folder 8-16)
    - General Correspondence, Undated Letters, A-H, circa 1910-1979 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - General Correspondence, Undated Letters, K-W, circa 1910-1979 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - General Correspondence, Unidentified Correspondents, circa 1910-1979 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Writings, circa 1940s-1979, 1.3:
    Writings by Andrew Dasburg include two brief essays on painting and an essay on abstract art entitled "Notes for a Criticism" that he wrote for the Harwood Foundation in 1953. Writings by others include poetry written by Peggy Church, sent to Dasburg for Christmas over several years, one of which is entitled "Andrew's Tree in the Moonlight", as well as poems and song lyrics written by Dasburg's wife, Marina Wister Dasburg. Filed here are writings and research notes by Teles Romero's on the conditions of the Jicarilla Apaches Indian reservation, a topic of particular interest to Marina Dasburg. Also found are draft writings by Virginia Gardner for her book, Friend and Lover: The Life of Louise Bryant. Andrew Dasburg and Grace Mott Johnson were friends with Bryant and Andrew and Alfred Dasburg assisted Gardner in her research for the book. Additional research material compiled by Gardner and found here includes photocopies of news clippings and articles on Bryant.
    Writings about Andrew Dasburg consist of a portion of an essay by Howard Cook, a biographical essay about Dasburg by Mary Carroll Nelson, an essay by Mabel Dodge Luhan regarding Dasburg's mural at the Colorado Springs Art Centre, and an essay regarding Dasburg's artwork by Van Deren Coke. There is also a document in German possibly written by Dasburg's grandfather, and other notes by unidentified authors. Folders are arranged by author and items are arranged chronologically within each folder.
    - Writings by Andrew Dasburg, 1953, undated (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Peggy Church, Poetry for Andrew Dasburg, 1950s (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Marina Wister Dasburg, Miscellaneous Writings, circa 1940s (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Virginia Gardner, Draft Writings and Research Material on Louise Bryant, circa 1972-1979 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Mary Carroll Nelson, Essay about Andrew Dasburg, 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Teles R. Romero, Writings and Research on Indians of Jicarilla Apaches, circa 1940s (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Miscellaneous Writings about Andrew Dasburg, 1959-1978 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Miscellaneous Writings and Notes by Others, circa 1970s (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Printed Material, 1922-1980, 1.4:
    Printed material concerns Dasburg's career, as well as his interest and participation in art events in New Mexico. Found here are three books, two specifically on artists in Taos, and one written by Dasburg's friend, Mabel Dodge Luhan. Other materials include exhibition announcements and catalogs for various group shows featuring artists of New Mexico, as well as solo exhibitions of Dasburg's work and the work of others. News clippings are about Dasburg, Taos news and art community, art exhibitions, and articles about his friends and family. Also found are newsletters from various New Mexico art organizations, blank postcards, some of which depict Woodstock, New York, a few press releases for exhibitions, and various programs and brochures. Items are arranged chronologically within each folder.
    - Books (Box 5)
      - Nordfeldt the Painter, Van Deren Coke, 1972, (Not scanned) (Box 5, Folder 28)
      - Taos and Its Artists, Mabel Dodge Luhan, 1947, (Not scanned) (Box 5, Folder 29)
      - A Taos Mosaic, Claire Morrill, 1973, (Not scanned) (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Exhibition Announcements and Invitations, 1967-1980 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Exhibition Catalogs, 1947-1977, (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 32-33)
    - News Clippings, 1922-1959, (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 34-35)
    - News Clippings, 1960-1979, (2 folders) (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
    - News Clippings, Undated, circa 1922-1979 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Newsletters, 1936, 1973-1979, (Not scanned) (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Programs and Brochures, 1941-1968, 1979, (Not scanned) (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Press Releases, 1973-1975 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Postcards (Blank), circa 1920s, 1950s, (Not scanned) (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous Printed Material, circa 1950s-1979 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Photographs, circa 1900-1978, 1.5:
    There are photographs of Andrew Dasburg and his family, friends, colleagues, homes, and artwork. Photographs of Dasburg include portraits and candid photographs. A few particularly noteworthy photographs depict Dasburg painting on Monhegan Island, Maine, in 1913; outside of Mabel Dodge Luhan's cottage in Provincetown, Massachusetts; outside of Luhan's home in Taos, New Mexico; and painting in his studio in Taos. Photographs of Dasburg with friends and family include him with his mother and son, Alfred; in a group photograph of Birge Harrison's Art Students' League summer class in Woodstock, New York, in 1907 along with his future wife, Grace Mott Johnson; in his studio at 115 rue Notre Dame des Champs with friends in 1910; with Konrad Cramer and John Reed in 1914; with artist Charles Kassler in Colorado; and with other unidentified groups of people, probably in Woodstock, NY. Also found are photographs of his son Alfred as a child and with his wife and children; photographs of friend and fellow artist Lila Wheelock Howard; and photographs of the Wister children, including Dasburg's third wife, Marina Wister. Notable among the photographs of family and friends include snapshots of Florence Lucius, Konrad and Florence Ballin Cramer, Frieda and D. H. Lawrence, and Mabel Dodge Luhan.
    The papers also include several photographs taken at Taos, New Mexico, including two photographs of Andrew and Alfred Dasburg with Tony Luhan and a photograph of Alfred with Mary Foote, Mabel Dodge Luhan, and Tony Luhan en route to a snake dance. Additional photographs of Taos include Native American events, landscapes, and architecture. Photographs of places include Dasburg's house in Woodstock, New York, his mother's house in Wurtsboro, New York, Monhegan Island, Nova Scotia, and other unidentified places. Also found are photographs and slides of artwork by Dasburg and a few photographs of artwork by others. Folders are arranged by subject and chronologically within each folder.
    - Photographs of Andrew Dasburg, 1908-1970s, (4 folders) (Box 6, Folder 9-12)
    - Photographs of Andrew Dasburg with Friends & Family, circa 1910-1976 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Photographs of Alfred Dasburg & Family, circa 1912-1975 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Photographs of Lila Wheelock Howard, circa 1910s (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Photographs of Wister Children, circa 1902 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Photographs of Friends and Family, 1914-1978 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Photographs of Taos, New Mexico, 1920s-1930s (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Photographs of Models, circa 1920s (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Photographs of Nudes (Possibly Rose Davidson), 1911 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Unidentified Photographs of People, circa 1900-1960 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Photographs of Dasburg House in Woodstock, New York, circa 1920 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Photographs of Monhegan Island, 1913 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Photographs of Nova Scotia, circa 1910s (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Photograps of Places, circa 1900-1960 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Photographs of Animals, circa 1910s, (Not scanned) (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Photographs of Andrew Dasburg/Grace Mott Johnson Exhibition, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Photographs of Artwork by Dasburg, circa 1950s-1970s, (3 folders; not scanned) (Box 6, Folder 28-30)
    - Photographs of Artwork by Others, circa 1914-1970s, (Not scanned) (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Slides, Photographs of Andrew Dasburg, 1948, 1956, 1977-1978, (Not scanned) (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Slides, Photographs of Artwork by Dasburg, 1977-1978, (Not scanned) (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Artwork, undated, 1.6:
    Artwork by Andrew Dasburg includes three woodblock prints of "Girl with Yo-Yo" and two small drawings.
    - Artwork by Andrew Dasburg, undated (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Alfred Dasburg Papers, 1914-1980, 1.7:
    Filed here are documents created by Alfred Dasburg, Andrew Dasburg and Grace Mott Johnson's son. Included is correspondence between Alfred Dasburg and family members, friends, his step-mother Nancy Lane, as well as with universities, art galleries, and museums regarding the loan of artwork by Andrew Dasburg or requesting biographical information about Dasburg or Johnson. A significant amount of correspondence during the late 1970s is with Virginia Gardner who was researching Dasburg and Johnson's careers and friendships with Louise Bryant. Also found within the correspondence are letters regarding his parents' health care. By the mid-1970s Alfred was handling many of his father's business and financial affairs which is reflected in these letters.
    Correspondence between Alfred and his father, Andrew Dasburg, is found in series 1.2, and correspondence between Alfred and his mother, Grace Mott Johnson, is found in series 2.2. Additional material in Alfred Dasburg's papers include three of his report cards, his wife Matilda's death certificate, and documents from his trip to Dasburg, Germany. Items are arranged chronologically within each folder.
    - Alfred Dasburg Correspondence, 1914-1980, (7 folders) (Box 6, Folder 35-41)
    - Report Cards, 1924, 1927 (Box 6, Folder 42)
    - Death Certificate for Matlilda Sevier Dasburg, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 43)
    - Documents from Trip to Dasburg, Germany, 1964, (Not scanned) (Box 6, Folder 44)
    - Course Materials, Solid-State Electronics, 1967, (Not scanned) (Box 6, Folder 45)
- Grace Mott Johnson Papers, 1833-1963, Series 2:; (Box 7-10; 2.8 linear feet)
  The papers of Grace Mott Johnson document her personal life through extensive correspondence with family, friends, and fellow artists, as well as her writings, photographs and original artwork. To a lesser degree these papers document her career as an exhibiting sculptor and civil rights activist.
  Found within the Grace Mott Johnson papers are scattered biographical documents about the Grace and the Johnson families. Most of her papers consist of correspondence with family, including numerous letters to her son, Alfred Dasburg, friends, and fellow artists. Notable correspondents include John F. and Margaret Carlson, Florence Ballin Cramer, Jo Davidson, Florence Lucius, Walter Frankl, Lila Wheelock Howard, Henry Lee McFee, Mary Riley, Lee Simonson, Lindsey Morris Sterling, Alice Morgan Wright, Mabel Dodge Luhan, Vera Spier Kuhn, and others. Writings by Johnson include a very brief diary, poetry, her written account of two weeks in Taos, New Mexico, and other miscellaneous autobiographical writings. There are also a few writings by others. Scattered financial material includes receipts and account statements. Printed materials include one exhibition announcement and news clippings. Photographs are of Johnson, her family, friends, and works of art. Of note are photographs of Johnson with fellow artists, including a tintype of her with sculptors Florence Lucius and Jo Davidson. Johnson's artwork includes two folders of loose drawings and two sketchbooks, primarily of landscapes and animals.
  The Grace Mott Johnson Papers series is arranged into 7 subseries:
  2.1: Biographical Material, 1833, circa 1888-1935
  2.2: Correspondence, 1854, 1882-1963
  2.3: Writings, 1848-1950
  2.4: Financial Material, 1911-1952
  2.5: Printed Material, 1882, 1917-1950
  2.6: Photographs, 1880s-1940
  2.7: Artwork, circa 1890-1928
  Almost all of this series has been scanned in its entirety. A few materials not scanned include scattered financial records and a printed booklet unrelated to art.
  - Biographical Material, 1833, circa 1888-1935, 2.1:
    The small amount of biographical material found here includes Johnson family documents, such as list of births, as well as a draft of Grace Mott Johnson's will from 1912 and her brief biography for the publication "Leading Women of America." Legal documents include Johnson family property deeds and a legal agreement regarding Johnson's living accommodations while in Egypt. Also found are her Art Students' League membership card and three exhibition labels for her art work at the Pennsylvania Academy of the Fine Arts. Items are arranged chronologically within each folder.
    - Grace Mott Johnson and Johnson Family Biographical Documents, circa 1888-1935 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Johnson Family Legal Documents, 1833, 1924, 1929 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Art Students League Membership Card, 1913 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Exhibition Labels, 1912 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1854, 1882-1963, 2.2:
    Eighty years of Johnson's general correspondence primarily consists of personal letters with friends, family, and fellow artists. There is also a substantial amount of correspondence with her son, Alfred Dasburg. The bulk of the correspondence dates from 1906 to 1919.
    Because Alfred spent most of his childhood living in Taos with his father, Andrew Dasburg, or away at school or camp, Johnson's correspondence with her son provides very candid and detailed accounts of her daily activities. The letters discuss her current artwork, news from her friends and relatives, and her travels, including her stay in Taos, New Mexico in 1919. Also included are numerous letters written during her stay in a mental hospital from 1937 to 1938. Many of her later letters to Alfred include reminiscences of her youth and extensive self-analysis.
    General correspondence with other family and friends is extensive and most often discusses social events, news of family and friends, and other daily activities of the writer. Family correspondence includes numerous letters between Johnson and her siblings, especially her brother Van Cleve Johnson. Grace Mott Johnson corresponded with numerous painter and sculptor friends whom she met at the Art Students' League and in Woodstock, New York. Some of these include Marion Bullard, Russell Cowles, John F. and Margaret Carlson, Florence Ballin Cramer, Florence Lucius, Walter Frankl, Lila Wheelock Howard, with whom she shared a studio for a period of time, Thomas Hunt, Henry Lee McFee, Morgan Russell, Mary Riley, Lee Simonson, Lindsey Morris Sterling, and Alice Morgan Wright. Johnson was also close friends with the Davidson family, and found here is her correspondence with the sculptor Jo Davidson and his two sisters Ray and Rose. Other notable correspondence is with friend Vera Spier Kuhn, wife of artist Walt Kuhn, art patron Mable Dodge Luhan, journalist John Reed, gallery owner William Macbeth, and her psychiatrist Abraham Brill. Also found is a small amount of correspondence documenting Johnson's civil rights activities, including letters from the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People.
    This subseries also includes the correspondence of Frances H. Johnson, Grace Mott Johnson's aunt, also known as Aunt Fanny, with whom she was very close. Found here are postcards and letters from family and friends as well as numerous letters between Frances and Grace Mott Johnson, including several detailed letters from Grace describing her time in Taos.
    See Index B for a select list of correspondents.
    Index B: Correspondents from Series 2.2: Grace Mott Johnson Papers, General Correspondence
    Barclay, Jessie: 1909
    Bercinsky, David: 1911, 1929, undated
    Bercinsky, Rachel: 1906, 1908
    Bigelow, Poultney: 1910, 1911, undated
    Borglum, Gutzon: 1908
    Bradenburgh, Margaret Caspar: 1908, 1910, 1911, 1915, 1916, 1919, 1940
    Brill, Abraham A.: 1919, 1921, 1935, 1937-40, 1948
    Bullard, Eleanor: 1909
    Bullard, Marion: 1911, 1912, undated
    Cahen, J. B.: 1907
    Carlson, John F. & Margaret: 1907-1913, 1921, 1947
    Comeau, Martin F.: 1943, 1944
    Cook, Charles Bayley: 1911
    Cowles, Russell: 1909
    Cramer, Florence Ballin: 1907-1912, 1947, undated
    D'Andrea, Cecelia (Cecil): 1907, 1912, 1921
    Dasburg, Margaret: 1908, 1909, 1912, undated
    Dasburg, Matilda: 1940
    Davidson, Jo: 1906-1910
    Davidson, Ray: 1906-1914, 1930, 1932, 1938, 1940-1942, 1951
    Davidson, Rose: 1906-1913
    de Kerstrat, Yvonne: 1909
    Debling, Anna J.: 1909
    Denman, George: 1917
    Doepel, C. Henry: 1922
    Drew, Aline: 1937, undated
    Durgy, Caroline R.: 1908
    Eberle, A.: 1930
    Edson, Helen: 1908
    Ennis, C.: 1910
    Frankl, Walter H.: 1915, 1918, 1919, undated
    Friends Intelligencer: 1936
    Frost, Chris: 1914
    Gardin, Laura: 1908
    Geiger, Mary: 1914, 1922
    Gilbert, Carl H.: 1927
    Harls, E. B.: 1908
    Holden, C.: 1950
    Howard, Lila Wheelock: 1908-1911, 1914, 1918, 1923, undated
    Humphrey, T. F.: 1910
    Hunt, Dorothy: 1911
    Hunt, Thomas: 1908 (illustrated letter)
    Hutchinson, Mary: 1937
    Illava, Agatha: 1933
    Isler, Jacques: 1933
    Jackson, Harrison S.: 1935
    Johnson, Alfred: 1907, 1908, 1911, 1914-1916
    Johnson, Francis: 1937, 1947
    Johnson, Mark: 1904, 1906, 1909, 1918, 1954
    Johnson, Van Cleve: 1904, 1908-1918, 1938, 1942, 1947, undated
    Kalish Pharmacy: 1910
    Kleinert, H.: 1923
    Kuhn, Vera Spier: 1908-1912
    Labaree, Mary Fleming: 1931
    Lane, Mrs. Franklin: 1933
    Law, Ellen M.: 1910, 1912, 1922
    Lincoln University: 1931
    Lucius, Albert: 1922
    Lucius, Florence (Floss): 1908-1915, undated
    Luhan, Mabel Dodge: 1919, 1924, 1933
    Macbeth, William: 1911
    Macomb, Edith: 1920
    Macrum, Mrs. George: 1947
    Magee, R.: 1909, 1910
    Martin, Daniel S.: 1891
    McFee, Henry Lee: 1912, 1914, undated
    McKenzie, Ilya: 1909-1911
    Miles, John E.: 1938
    Milner, H. W.: 1910
    Morgan, Helen: 1907, 1908, 1911, 1912
    Morrell, Edith: 1910, 1911, undated
    Morton-Morris, Mrs. John: 1946
    Mott, Cora E.: 1908
    Mott, Jane: 1910
    Mott, Laura: 1894, 1906-1908
    National Association for the Advancement of Colored People: 1935-1937, 1940, undated
    National Association of Woment Painters and Sculptors: 1937
    The New York News: 1935
    Noyes, Minnie A.: 1916
    Odok, Effiom: 1938
    Pennsylvania Academy of Fine Arts: 1913
    Pfeiffer, J.: 1912
    Potterat, Mathilda: 1910, 1912
    Radcliffe, C. M. R.: 1912
    Raub, Ida: 1922
    Reed, John: 1916
    Reynolds, William E.: 1922
    Riley, Mary: 1909-1911, undated
    Rogers, Julia J.: 1911
    Rosenberg, Elfie Cahen: 1904-1912, 1926
    Russell, Morgan: 1908
    Schlisinger, Gisela: 1907
    Schuyler, Josephine: 1933
    Scott, Leon W.: 1935
    Sholtz, David: 1935
    Simkins, Martha: 1913
    Simonson, Lee: 1912, 1914-1917, 1928, undated
    Smith, S. Archibald: 1920
    Spanish and Indian Trading Co.: 1926
    Sterling, Lindsey Morris (Sally): 1908-1912
    Sutherland, Arthur: 1936-1939
    Teague, Cecil: 1911
    Teague, Walter: 1911
    Wardwell, James: 1909
    Watkins, Mary Jane: 1930
    Weeks, Henry de F.: 1910
    Weigand, Margarith: 1909-1914
    White, Mrs. John K.: 1908
    Wright, Alice Morgan: 1907, 1908, 1910, 1930
    Yaldo, Margaret: 1917-1919
    - Correspondence with Alfred Dasburg, 1914-1925, (6 folders) (Box 7, Folder 5-10)
    - Correspondence with Alfred Dasburg, 1931-1963, (6 folders) (Box 7, Folder 11-16)
    - General Correspondence, circa 1882-1894, 1901-1907, (6 folders) (Box 7, Folder 17-22)
    - General Correspondence, 1908, (6 folders) (Box 7, Folder 23-28)
    - General Correspondence, 1909, (7 folders) (Box 7, Folder 29-35)
    - General Correspondence, 1910, (5 folders) (Box 7, Folder 36-40)
    - General Correspondence, 1911, (7 folders) (Box 8, Folder 1-7)
    - General Correspondence, 1912-1914, (10 folders) (Box 8, Folder 8-17)
    - General Correspondence, 1915-1932, (8 folders) (Box 8, Folder 18-25)
    - General Correspondence, 1933-1954, (7 folders) (Box 8, Folder 26-32)
    - General Correspondence, Undated Letters, A-Z, circa 1900-1954 (Box 8, Folder 33)
    - General Correspondence, Letter Fragments and Drafts, circa 1940-1954 (Box 8, Folder 34)